Dream big.
The Peanuts Movie is a comedy, animation, family film directed by Steve Martino.
Snoopy embarks upon his greatest mission as he and his team take to the skies to pursue
their arch-nemesis, while his best pal Charlie Brown begins his own epic quest.
Charlie Brown (voice), played by Noah Schnapp.
Snoopy / Woodstock (voice) (archive sound), played by Bill Melendez.
Franklin Armstrong (voice), played by Marleik 'Mar Mar' Walker.
Linus (voice), played by Alex Garfin.
Lucy van Pelt (voice), played by Hadley Belle Miller.
Marcie (voice), played by Rebecca Bloom.
The Peanuts Movie (known in some countries as Snoopy and Charlie Brown: The Peanuts
Movie) is a 2015 American animated comedy film based on Charles M.
Schulz's comic strip Peanuts.
Directed by Steve Martino from a screenplay by Cornelius Uliano and Craig and Bryan Schulz (Schulz's son and grandson, respectively), the
film stars the voices of Noah Schnapp as Charlie Brown and, via archival recordings, Bill Melendez as Snoopy and Woodstock.
It was produced by 20th Century Fox Animation and Blue Sky
Studios, and distributed by 20th Century Fox.
The film sees Charlie trying to improve his odds with his love interest, the Little Red-Haired Girl, while Snoopy writes a book where he is
a World War I Flying Ace trying to save his fellow pilot and love interest, Fifi, from the Red Baron and his flying circus.
It was the fifth full-length Peanuts film and the first in 35 years,
following Bon Voyage, Charlie Brown (and Don't Come Back!!).
Development of the film began in 2006, six years after the death of Charles
Schulz and the final release of the last Peanuts comic strip.
Craig Schulz, a son of Charles, pitched a film idea to his son, Bryan Schulz.
20th Century Fox and Blue Sky Studios announced development of a computer-animated film in October 2012, a year after
Happiness is a Warm Blanket, Charlie Brown, with Martino directing, due to his faithfulness to the style of Dr.
Seuss in the film, Horton Hears a Who!
(2008), also produced by Blue Sky.
Numerous elements from the comic strip were featured in the film, such as Charlie Brown's skating pond, his house, "the
wall" and Lucy's psychiatrist booth, as well as the Snoopy and Woodstock voice tracks from Bill Melendez.
The score was composed by Christophe Beck, with additional
soundtrack contributions by Meghan Trainor and David Benoit.
The Peanuts Movie premiered in New York City on November 1, 2015, and was
released in the United States five days later on November 6.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed $246 million worldwide
against a $99 million budget to become the 7th highest-grossing animated film of 2015.
It received nominations for the Annie Award for Best Animated Feature, the Critics' Choice Movie Award for Best Animated Feature
and was the first Blue Sky Studios film to be nominated for a Golden Globe Award for Best Animated Feature Film.
The film explores themes of based on comic, computer
animation, red baron, family, comic strip.
The tone is lighthearted.